Finding Aid for University of Michigan. Dept. of Medicine and Surgery Theses, 1851-1878
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Medical Theses
  - Class of 1873
    - Potter, De La Motte, "Intermittent Fever", 1873 (Reel 46)
    - Raynor, Edwin West (d. 1893), "Hygiene as a Preventative of and Remedy in Disease", 1873 (Reel 46)
    - Schenk, Noah (d. 1880), "Pneumonitis", 1873 (Reel 46)
    - Short, John Larimer (d. 1912), "Typhoid Fever", 1873 (Reel 46)
    - Smith, Samuel Finley (d. 1923), "Tubercle", 1873 (Reel 46)
    - Smith, Samuel Leigh Southard, "Reproduction", 1873 (Reel 46)
    - Snook, Jerome Marvin (d. 1902), "Acute Pneumonitis", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Solis, William Henry (d. 1885), "Digestion", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Stevens, Benjamin Cotton (d. 1908), "Hip Joint Disease", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Stuart, Charles Gregor (d. 1886), "Digestion", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Turner, Abram Reynolds (d. 1879), "Typhoid Fever", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Wardell, Joshua Mearne (d. 1932), "Blood", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Watson, Edward (d. 1901), "Typhoid Fever", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Weirick, Thomas Hudson (d. 1918), "Cataract, with Preliminary Remarks on the Anatomy of the Eye", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Whitbeck, Cornelia Elizabeth (d. 1915), "Dislocation of the Soulder Joint", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Whiting, Clarence Melville (d. 1884), "Dyspepsia", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Whitney, Charles Howard (d. 1880), "Pneumonia", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Wightman, Samuel James (d. 1900), "Cerebrum", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Wilson, James Harvey (d. 1899), "Enteric or Typhoid Fever", 1873 (Reel 47)
    - Wright, Peter Wesley (d. 1909), SEE listing for, 1872 (Reel 47)
    - Wyman, Hal Clement (d. 1908), "Hemorrhage", 1872 (Reel 47)
  - Class of 1874
    - Barrett, James Morris, "Hernia", 1874 (Reel 47)
    - Beach, Judson (d. 1917), "Digestion", 1874 (Reel 47)
    - Beebe, Ethel Cushman (d. 1886), "Spermatorrhoea", 1874 (Reel 47)
    - Benham, Frank Adelbert, "Sexual Physiology", 1874 (Reel 47)
    - Berneike, Marion Louise (Rice), "Organic Renal Excretions", 1874 (Reel 47)
    - Bodemann, Frank Ellis (d. 1884), "Inflammation and Tubercle", 1874 (Reel 47)
    - Bonnet, William Mervin (d. 1921), "Epilepsy", 1874 (Reel 47)
    - Bordner, William Henry Harrison (d. 1907), "Incidental Causes of Disease", 1874 (Reel 47)
    - Broucher, David Kreps (d. 1890), "Physical and Vital Force", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Chambers, John Drake, "Electricity, its History, Phenomena and Therapeutical Application", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Chambers, John William (d. 1915), on rheumatism, 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Cucaden, Gertrude (Jones), "Syphilis", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Davis, Charles Edward, "Ethics of Medical Eclecticism", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Desnoyers, Dontague (d. 1918), "La Scrofule", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Flagg, John Henry, "Spontaneous Generation", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Ford, Harrison, "Refraction and Accommodation of the Eye", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Goodwin, Fairfield (d. 1918), "Typhoid Fever", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Greenfield, John Wesley, "Diphtheria", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Heller, Josiah (d. 1904), "Purulent Ophthalmia", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Higgins, Samuel George (d. 1886), "Natural Labor", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Hill, Frank Clair (d. 1892), "Gonorrhoea", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Hill, Nancy Maria (d. 1919), "Puerperal Fever", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Hume, Charles Robinson, "Menstruation, its Phenomena, and Supposed Relation to Ovulation", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Humiston, Charles Beaney (d. 1913), "Acute Lobar Pneumonitis", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Hutton, William (d. 1903), "Pneumonitis", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Kelly, Martin Crocker (d. 1898), "Croupous Pneumonitis" [Degree granted in 1875], 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Kenyon, Mary (d. 1899), "Blood", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Kerr, George Washington (d. 1916), "Fractures and Dislocations Occuring at the Elbow Joint with Their Appropriate Treatment", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Kollock, Harriet Margaret (d. 1883), "Alcoholism", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Lawrence, Tinnie Sarah (d. 1882), "Nutrition", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Lee, Mary Victoria (d. 1892), "The Relations of the Physician to Society", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - Lowry, George Washington (d. 1922), "Animal Heat", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - McCarty, Rufus Halsey (d. 1890), "Opium", 1874 (Reel 48)
    - McCaslin, William Alfred (d. 1915), "Syphilis", 1874 (Reel 49)
    - Manzer, Seymour Arzeno (d. 1886), "Surgery", 1874 (Reel 49)
    - Marr, William Lawrence (d. 1910), "Opium Eating", 1874 (Reel 49)
    - Martin, George, "Leucorrhoea", 1874 (Reel 49)
    - Miller, Thomas Owen (d. 1888), SEE listing for, 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Moore, Frank Pierce (d. 1908), "Fissure in Ano or Painful Irritable Ilcer of the Rectum", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Moore, Nathan B. (d. 1904), "Typhoid Fever", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Morrow, Olive Jane (Emerson), "Embryology", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Newkirk, Maitland Featherson, "Typhoid Fever", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Northup, William Thomas (d. 1887), "Blood", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Parker, Addis Emmet (d. 1890), "Gonorrhoea", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Phelps, Herbert Charles (d. 1918), "Pneumonia", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Place, John Fields (d. 1912), "Cataract", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Powell, Jehu Z. (d. 1918), "The Influence of the Mind upon the Body", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Putney, Lorenzo Sylvanus (d. 1908), "Carbonate of Ammonia", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Rhodes, Emmet Camelio (d. 1915), "Syphilis", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Richmond, Tyler Webster (d. 1904), "Digestion", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Riley, Thomas (d. 1901), "Lithotomy", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Rinkle, LaFayette (d. 1911), "Hypodermic Medication", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Seeley, Frank Taylor, "Digestion", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Senier, Alfred (d. 1918), "The Functions of the Nervous system with Special Reference to the Brain", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Shoemaker, William Patterson (d. 1889), "Respiration", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Sidlinger, Samuel Hoffman, "Cholera Infantum", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Smith, Walter Winslow, "The Phenomena of Inflammation", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Sparhawk, Theron Augustus (d. 1874), "Variola", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Stevens, William Corning, "Scarlatina", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Taylor, Asher Columbus, "The Blood", 1873 (Reel 49)
    - Taylor, Olive Malvina (Patton) (d. 1906), "Typhoid Fever", 1873 (Reel 50)
    - Tidball, Jasper (d. 1911), "Gonorrhoea", 1873 (Reel 50)
    - Tidball, Leander (d. 1905), "Variola", 1873 (Reel 50)
    - Tiffany, Flavil Benjamin (d. 1918), "Peritonitis", 1873 (Reel 50)
    - Underwood, Rachel Abbie, "Hysteria", 1873 (Reel 50)
    - Walbridge, John Solon (d. 1920), "Scarlatina", 1873 (Reel 50)
    - Ward, Clarence Stanton (d. 1921), "Diptheria" (sic), 1873 (Reel 50)
    - Welsh, George (d. 1899), "Intermittent Fever", 1873 (Reel 50)
    - White, William Whitfield, "Acute Peritonitis", 1873 (Reel 50)
    - Young, John (d. 1912), "Acute Tonsilitis", 1873 (Reel 50)
  - Class of 1875
    - Alleman, Joseph Judson (d. 1904), "Scarlatina", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Austin, Hiram William, "Diphtheria", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Bacon, Martin Wright (d. 1922), "Management of Natural Labor", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Baker, George Griswold, "Chronic Cervical Endometritis", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Baldwin, Newton, "A Synopsis of Intermittent Fever and its Treatment", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Briggs, Josephine Shaw (d. 1904), "The Physiology and Pathology of the Urine", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Briggs, Solon, "Scarlatina", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Campbell, Oliver Boyer (d. 1912), "Circulation of the Blood", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Case, William Newton (d. 1919), "Malarial Fever", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Cotton, Robert McKown Higley, "Alcohol, Is it a Food?", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Darling, George Sylvester (d. 1908), "Typhoid Fever", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Davis, Sylvester Byron (d. 1917), "Intermittent Fever", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Dayton, David French (d. 1908), "Notes on Reproduction", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Deuel, Elisabeth Lord (d. 1900), "Mental Influence", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Egbert, Rufus Alvin (d. 1918), "Scarlet Fever", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Fitzpatrick, Edmund (d. 1880), "Typhoid Fever", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Fauzdik (Fosdick), Marvin, "The Blood", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Frissell, Seraph (d. 1915), "The Liver and its Diseases", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Gerow, Elizabeth Hait, "Origin and Destiny of the Products of Inflammation", 1875 (Reel 50)
    - Gleason, Adele Amelia, "Insomnia", 1875 (Reel 51)
    - Green, Clinton Rogers (d. 1894), "Typhoid Fever", 1875 (Reel 51)
    - Gunn, John Alexander (d. 1916), "Digestion", 1875 (Reel 51)
    - Hagadorn, Allen F. (d. 1905), "Apoplexy", 1875 (Reel 51)
    - Harrison, George Martin, "Typhoid Fever", 1875 (Reel 51)
    - Hartley, Sophia Meindermann (d. 1917), SEE listing for, 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Harvey, George (d. 1892), "The History of the Clinic", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Hay, James Duffield, "Digestion", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Herdman, William James (1848-1906), "Record of Surgical Clinics from January 1st to March 24, 1875", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Higbee, Lewis Edward (d. 1908), "Scarlet Fever", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Holland, Marion (d. 1922), "History of Vaccination", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Hosken, Joseph Barzella (d. 1906), "Typhoid Fever", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Hubbard, Charles Wallace (d. 1900), "Epidemic Cholera", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Hutchings, Guy (d. 1922), "Inflammation", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Jenkins, Frederick Decimus (d. 1898), "For I am Fearfully and Wonderfully Made", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Johnson, Colonel Manfred, "Hypertrophy of the Prostate", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Keeney, John Calvin (d. 1907), "Inflammation", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Kelley, Louis Lorenzo, "Alimentation", 1873 (Reel 51)
    - Kelly, Martin Crocker (d. 1898), SEE listing for, 1874 (Reel 51)
    - Ketcham, William John (d. 1915), "Inflammation", 1874 (Reel 51)
    - Kimball, Edwin Leroy, "Stricture of the Uretha", 1874 (Reel 51)
    - Kirk, John Hillis (d. 1898), "Development of the Ovum", 1874 (Reel 51)
    - Lawrence, Robert Richard (d. 1919), "Epidemic Cholera", 1874 (Reel 51)
    - Livingstone, Henry Drummond (d. 1920), on urethral stricture, 1874 (Reel 51)
    - McCallum, Neil A. (d. 1888), "Fevers", 1874 (Reel 51)
    - McCandless, Morris Dexter (d. 1892), "Scarlatina", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - McCrea, Henry (d. 1914), "Syphilis", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - McCullough, John Black (d. 1904), "De Opio", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - McKibben, Frank Stewart, "The Physician and his Work", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Maddox, Leander Erastus (d. 1920), "Acute Lobar Pneumonitis", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Millard, Caroline Amelia (Hollister), "Digestion", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Mosher, Eliza Maria (1846-1928), "The Structure and Function of the Ovaries", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Murphy, Richard (d. 1894), "Intermittent Fever", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Paulding, Ormond Pinkerton, "Sick Headache", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Pease, George Chancy (d. 1895), "Alcohol", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Piper, Richard Joseph, "Etiology, or the Cause of Disease", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Porter, Charles Virgin, "Causes and Treatment of Consumption", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Post, Justin Ellis, "General Inflammation", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Prindle, Edward C. (d. 1921), "Effect of Moisture on Malarial Fever" [Degree granted in 1876], 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Raymond, John Underwood (d. 1914), "The Thermometer in Disease", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Richardson, A. Adelaide (d. 1885), "Thrombus and Embolus", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Rothwell, Edwin James (d. 1920), "The Skeleton", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Rowe, Edward Jackson (d. 1897), "Acute Articular Rheumatism", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Sanford, George Elmer (d. 1907), "Physiology of the Circulatory System", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Shannon, George Gordon (d. 1900), "Diphtheria", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Shaw, Eliza Ann, "Diseases of the Nervous System", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Steiner, Henry Lewis (d. 1880), "Rachitis", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Stockwell, Sarah Fowler (d. 1904), "Peruvian Bark" [Degree granted in 1876], 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Strong, Martha Cochrane (1843-1926), "Abortion", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Swan, Edwin Augustine, "Menstruation", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Thomson, John F., "Phthisis", 1874 (Reel 52)
    - Tremper, Robert Haines, "Anaesthetics and Their Use", 1874 (Reel 53)
    - Turner, Clifford Afton (d. 1907), "An Evil" [syphilis], 1874 (Reel 53)
    - Ultes, Charles (d. 1916), "Interstitial Inflammation", 1874 (Reel 53)
    - Upjohn, William Cyrenus, "The Course and Treatment of Erysipelas", 1874 (Reel 53)
    - Upjohn, William Erastus, "Fracture of the Femur", 1874 (Reel 53)
    - Vincent, Mary Lucinda (d. 1921), "Nervous System", 1874 (Reel 53)
    - Walker, Marie Josephine (d. 1882), "Care of Children", 1874 (Reel 53)
    - Watson, Clark (d. 1899), "Opium", 1874 (Reel 53)
    - Williams, Freeman Simmons, "Opium", 1874 (Reel 53)
    - Wright, Olin Seymour, "Diphtheria", 1874 (Reel 53)
  - Class of 1876
    - Anderson, James (d. 1908), "Diphtheria", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Barnum, Elbert Eugene (d. 1907), "Diphtheria", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Begel, Charles Ephraim (d. 1901), "Cinchona", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Birdsall, William Randall (d. 1892), "The Report of a Case of Indolent Ulcer of the Leg", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Birmingham, Henry Patrick, "Primary Syphilis", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Bisbee, Don Alvardo, "Wounds", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Broek, Albert (d. 1876), "The Model Physician", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Brundage, George Alson (d. 1887), "Spermatorrhoea", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Burgess, Josephus Martin, "The History of a Case", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Campbell, Alexander X., "Typhoid Fever", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Campbell, John F. (d. 1914), "Pneumonia", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Campbell, John Oscar (d. 1904), "Inflammation", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Casebeer, Howard Maxwell, "Vital Fluid", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Chamberlin, Charles Sumner (d. 1912), "Salicylic Acid as an Anti-periodic", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Chamberlin, H. Dewey (d. 1921), "Tetanus", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Chandler, Clement Long (d. 1892), "Enteric Fever", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Connor, Caroline (Nielsen), "Iritis", 1876 (Reel 53)
    - Cosens, Abby (Pease) (d. 1905), "Narcotics", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Cosens, Richard (d. 1895), "Typhoid Fever", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Cruickshank, Charles Glanville (d. 1904), "Cysts", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Devinney, Clifford Lavega (d. 1908), "Acute Rheumatism", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Dickinson, Amasa John (d. 1888), "Chronic Cervical Endometritis", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Duehr, Ulrich Adolf (d. 1905), "Einige Angeboren Formfehler des Mund Partis", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Ellinwood, Eliza Maria (d. 1920), "Lead Poisoning", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Forsyth, Mary Jane, "Mental Derangement", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Garrison, Ira Mesick, "Common Croupous Pneumonia", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Georg, John (d. 1888), "Homeopathy", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Godfrey, Willoughby Lyman, "Dysentery", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Gregory, Idris Helen (Briggs) (d. 1921), "Malarial Fevers", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Hammond, Horace William (d. 1910), "Malarial Fevers", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Hanson, David Scott, "Inflammation", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Hatch, Henry Bishop, "Yellow Fever", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Hauxhurst, John Walker, "Typhoid Fever", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Hill, Alonzo Ward, "Circulation of the Blood", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Howell, Phoebe Delinda (Bullock) (d. 1880), "Hints on Hygiene", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Hyde, Charles Carroll, "Diptheria" (sic), 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Hyde, Merrill James, "Circulation", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Kerwin, Michael Hamilton (d. 1891), "Digestion", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - King, Mabel Beecher (1831-1920), "Eclampsia Puerperalis", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Kingston, Robert John, "Diptheria" (sic), 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Kremers, Henry (d. 1914), "Progress of the Medical Profession", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Latimer, Frank Newton, "New Remedies", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Lee, John (d. 1903), "Pneumonia", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Lindsay, Catherine (1842-1923), "The Importance of Understanding and Avoiding the Causes of Disease", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Logan, Robert (d. 1903), "Anatomy and Function of the Spleen", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Longacre, Harmon Yerkes (d. 1911), "Indigestion", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - Luscomb, Charles Edwin, "Cancer", 1876 (Reel 54)
    - McDonald, Donald Alexander (d. 1910), "Cholera", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - McGregor, Peter (d. 1914), "Typhoid Fever", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - McKellar, Duncan (d. 1917), "Pneumonia", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Mellen, William Michael Edward (d. 1906), "Phthisis Pulmonalis", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Millspaugh, Joseph Gillespie, "Bromide of Potassium", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Mitchell, Mina Annette (Baker), "Acute Mania", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Moore, Joseph James (d. 1909), "Scarlatina", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Moulding, Frank Carpenter, "Alcohol", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Murray, Byron J., "Typhoid Fever", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Norris, Martha Marcella (1850-1917), "Diphtheria", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - O'Neill, George Cydro DeLozere (d. 1920), "A Midnight Call", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Oven, Thomas P. (d. 1912), "Cataract", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Palmer, Emory Clark, "Puerperal Convulsions (Eclampsia)", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Palmer, Ezra Augustin (d. 1909), "Malarial or Periodic Fever", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Palmer, George Calder (d. 1917), "Typhoid Fever", 1876 (Reel 55)
    - Prindle, Edward C. (d. 1921), SEE listing for, 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Radley, Samuel David (d. 1883), "Acute Bronchitis", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Rice, Cyrus Strickler (d. 1899), "Preeminence of Anatomy in the Medical Profession", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Seeley, John Sanford, "Our Science and What I Know About It", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Shaffer, John Rings, "Enuresis Occurring in Children", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Snodgrass, Henry Lane, "Vaccination", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Stocking, Jerome Daniel (d. 1918), "Anaesthesia", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Stockwell, Sarah Fowler (d. 1904), SEE listing for, 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Taylor, Joseph Hume (d. 1904), "Typhoid Fever", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Terry, Will Gaylord (d. 1885), "Iritis", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Thompson, James Albert, "Iodine", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Traver, Richard Cunningham (d. 1908), "Dietetic Regimen for Children", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Travis, John Jacob (d. 1909), "Typhoid Fever", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Upjohn, Millie Kirby (1852-1920), "Leucorrhoea", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Van Velsor, Henry V. (d. 1896), "Inflammation", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Wallace, Daniel James, "Pneumonia", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Ward, Sylvia M. (d. 1915), "Phthisis Pulmonalis", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - Weed, Albert Earnest, "Diabetes", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - West, Charles Franklin (d. 1907), "Phthisis", 1875 (Reel 55)
    - White, Homer Harvey, "Causes and Treatment of Epilepsy", 1875 (Reel 56)
    - Young, Elisha Mason (d. 1880), "Malarial Fever", 1875 (Reel 56)
    - Young, Mary Jane (Rising) (d. 1912), "Disinfectants", 1875 (Reel 56)
  - Class of 1877
    - Allyn, Charles Beckwith (d. 1885), "Amputation", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Anderson, Elnora A. Upham (Totten) (d. 1882), "Puerperal Fever", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Anderson, William Walter (d. 1890), "A Dissertation on Thesis", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Andrews, Albion Alexander (d. 1904), "Public Health", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Armstrong, Oscar Samuel, "Croupous Pneumonia" [with accompanying documents: "Pneumonia" by W. Russell, "Brights Disease of the Kidneys" by unknown author, and "Pus" by E.W. Grover], 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Ayres, George Byron (d. 1890), "Hair Lip", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Ballintine, Eva (Eveline) Phebe (d. 1921), "Management of Natural Labor", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Barrows, Ransom Moore, "Hydrophobia", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Batchelder, Orville Benjamin, "Circulation of the Blood", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Black, Charles (d. 1884), "Quaestio de Amenorrhoea", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Bradfield, Benjamin Dean, "Transmission of Life", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Burns, Alexander Clarkson (d. 1907), "Catarrh of Small and Large Intestines in Children", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Campbell, Daniel St. Clair (d. 1901), "Bronchitis", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Canfield, Harris Ansel, "Alcoholism", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Clark, John Edward, "Vis Medicatrix Naturae", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Conner, John Jay Hardin (d. 1909), "Dysentery", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Coughlin, Jeremiah, "Disinfectants", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - David, Edgerton Clapp (d. 1916), "Alcohol", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - David, Julius Worthington Y., "Nutrition", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Dennis, Henry William, "Morbid Urine", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Desjardins, Alfred (d. 1902), "De la Saignee" (sic), 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Dickinson, Emma Louise (Benham), "Cinchona", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Dudley, John Benjamin, "Bronchitis, Its Causes, Pathology, Diagnosis, and Treatment", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Dumon, John H., "Cerebro Spinal Meningitis, its Nature, Causation, and Treatment", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Elder, Guilford Dudley (d. 1906), "Gangrene", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Fugate, Stephen, "Stricture of the Urethra", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Furey, Whitefield George (d. 1910), "Morbus Coxarius", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Goodrich, Leslie Medard (d. 1880), "Pulmonary Tuberculosis", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Grant, Frederick Eugene (d. 1916), "Some of the General Causes of Disease", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Grover, Thomas Edward Walton, "Opium", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Halsted, Henry Powell, "Well Water", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Howell, Euphemia Jane (d. 1923), "Abbreviated Gestation", 1877 (Reel 56)
    - Ingram, Aaron Rood, "Diphtheria", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Ingram, John Smith (d. 1907), "The Progress of Medicine", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Jones, George Henry, "Croupous Pneumonia", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Lyon, James Johnson, "Personal Observations from a Preceptor's Practice", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - McKenzie, William Hamilton, "Typhoid Fever", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Maloney, Jeremiah Lynch (d. 1885), "Fractures", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Marchant, Juliet Elfrida, "Catarrhus Autumnalis" [with accompanying document: "Tuberculosis or Consumption" by O. B. Batchelder], 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Mitchell, Eliza Markell (d. 1922), "Hysteria", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Moss, Arthur Howard (d. 1880), "Rickets", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Newkirk, Moses, "Scarlatina", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Newton, George Adolphus (d. 1918), "Ulcers", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - North, Lucian Gregory, "Typhoid Fever", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Palmer, George William, "Notes on Intermittent Fever", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Paterson, Duncan (d. 1911), "Stricture", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Persons, Clarence Edward, "Scarlatina", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Royce, George Irwin, "The Value of Hygiene in Medicine", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Russell, William (d. 1910), "Derangement of the Nervous System and Its Accompanying Phenomena", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Schuyler, Randall, "Inflammation", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Sherrick, Jacob Danforth (d. 1921), "Circulation", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Sigler, Hollis Fred, "Alcohol", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Smith, Stewart Whedon, "Two Uses of Medical Electricity", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Stearns, Samuel Seymour (d. 1886), "Oxaluria", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Stuch, Lafayette (d. 1914), "Intermittent Fever", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Swift, Clarence Fletcher (d. 1920), "Erysipelas", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Tenny, Frances Augusta (d. 1912), "The Proper Care of Children", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Travis, James Henry, "Angular Curvature of the Spine, Pott's Disease", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Upjohn, Mary Lee (Hoagland), "Alimentation", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Vaill, Abbie Everest (d. 1897), "The Atmosphere, Its Relations to Health and Disease", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Vandivert, Ashman Henry, "Therapeutic Value of Quinidia, Cinchona, and Cinchonidia Compared with Quinia", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Volland, Sophia (Dean) (d. 1897), "Catarrhus Autumnalis", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Walbridge, Franklin Eugene, "Clinical History of Pulmonary Tuberculosis", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Watson, George (d. 1901), "Surgery", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Wheeler, Henry Mason, "Post Partum Hemorrhage", 1877 (Reel 57)
    - Wilder, George James, "Purulent Ophthalmia", 1877 (Reel 57)